Dr Vitalii Shkoldin / ויטלי שקולדין

Engineer

As a proficient physicist in optics and semiconductors, I possess a strong analytical mindset and additionally broad experience in high-tech. I readily absorb new knowledge and can solve complex problems through innovative solutions. Moreover, I place high value on user experience.

Work Experience:

<u>Deeplay.io</u> – Al-driven animators for card games

July 2023 - now | Data Engineer

- Engineering algorithms for data workflows in Apache Airflow
- Optimized data processing using python scripting and enhanced SQL performance across ClickHouse, MySQL
- Maintaing documentation.

Pet project - VPN service

Jan 2023 – Jan 2024 | Full stack

Self-learning: - Certified in Cloud Services (DevOps, Yandex);

- SQL for Analytics; Docker (Karpov.Courses).

ITMO University & Alferov University

Leading universities in the field of nanophotonics and semiconductors.

May 2017 – Dec 2022 | 5.5 years | Research engineer | Data acquisition & Data Analyst

- Assembling optical setups and direct involvement in execution of optical experiments (spectrometers, lasers, vacuum chambers etc... <u>detailed list on the second page</u>)
- Performing analysis and automation of experimental data processing using Python (Pandas) and data visualization employing Matplotlib and Seaborn for presentations in publications and conferences
- Enhancing equipment capabilities through the use of microcontrollers (C++, LabView)
- Conducting market and technological research
- Secured 5 research grants (application, managing, teamwork, reporting)

NT-SPb — a scientific equipment manufacturer specializing in atomic force microscopy and a spin-off of the global giant NT-MDT.

May 2018 - Sep 2022 | 4 years | Engineer

- Engaging in R&D and customizing equipment to meet client specifications
- Performing on-site and remote equipment installations, support
- Conducting software and hardware testing

loffe Institute June 2012 – May 2017 | 5 years | System Administrator & Student

- Research, Data analysis and processing with Python, NumPy, MATLAB

Local ISP Sep 2011 – May 2013 | 2 years | System Administrator

 Adept at efficiently tailoring **Debian Linux** to suit any specific objectives (**iptables, BASH**)

Zoo.SPb.ru – Online Pet Store

2009 – 2011 | 2 years | Full stack engineer

- Full Stack Web Developer (LAMP stack, deployment, support, CMS implementation, front-end design, content management, optimization, and PHP module development)
- Odoo administration (ERP & CRM system), PostgreSQL, synchronization, custom Python module development
- Predicting the purchases of each customer.
- Integration with transportation logistics systems for delivery scheduling, time allocation (up to 15 min precision), and SMS notifications via API.

Israeli citizenship

ShkoldinVA@gmail.com

+972 55 7707 387

Telegram: @binSmile

GitHub.com/binSmile

<u>LinkedIn.com/in/</u>
<u>vitaliy-shkoldin/</u>

Additional experience

Math Statistics, Algorithm
Solving, Git, YouTrack, JIRA,
PyCharm, DataSpell,
Jupyter,
Basics of Machine Learning,
Orange Data Mining tool,
advanced Microsoft Excel,
Apache AirFlow, dbt,
ClickHouse, SQL,
Redash, LaTeX, electrical
circuits, DIY IoT

Education

Ph.D. in Physics
Cond-matter physics
June 2022 | St. Petersburg
ITMO University

M.Sc. & B.Sc.
Electronics and
nanoelectronics
2011 - 2017 | St. Petersburg
Polytechnic University

Languages

- o English
- o Russian (native)

Related scientific background

I have extensive experience with:

- Scanning Probe Microscopy (AFM and especially tunneling microscopy)
- Scanning Electron Microscopy
- Focused Electron Beam-Indused Deposition
- Optical microspectroscopy
- Spatial manipulation with nanoparticles
- Vacuum equipment work and service
- o Reverse engineering of equipment protocols
- Coupling different equipment
- Big data array analysis and data manipulation automation
- Programming on Python (NumPy, Pandas...), LabView and easy operate with different internal hardware languages
- Big data array analysis and data manipulation automation
- o Programming on Python (Pandas, Numpy, beautifulsoup4, pyserial...), Bash
- o LabView and easy operate with different internal hardware languages (ex. Motorized Stage...)

Familiar with:

- Thorlabs optical components;
- AIST-NT SmartSPM and Combiscope, atomic force microscopes with optical access;
- Scienta Omicron VT AFM XA 50/500 and VT650 Ultra-Hight vacuum scanning probe microscope
- NT-MDT and NT-SPb various atomic force microscopes;
- FEI Quanta Inspect S scanning electron microscope;
- Zeiss Crossbeam Neon 40b scanning electron microscope;
- Kleindiek Nanomanipulator MM3A-EM (nanoparticle manipulation in SEM);
- Horiba LabRAM HR-800 Raman spectrometer;
- Princeton Instruments SpectraPro SP-2500 high-sensitivity spectrometer;
- Various fiber spectrometers (Avantes, OceanInsight, etc.);
- Keithley Instruments and Tektronix equipment;
- Hand-made optical setups;
- Hand-made motorization and automation based on Arduino and ESP8266.